<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lorisscandurra</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on lorisscandurra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://lsca94.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My lunilo.live journey</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/lunilo-live-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/lunilo-live-journey/</guid><description>On the 10th of November 2020, a friend added me to a group call to discuss a startup idea. It was my friend, a guy I didn&amp;rsquo;t know yet, and me in the group call. The guy I didn&amp;rsquo;t know, named Luzius, had the idea to bring local artists, entertainers, comedians, performers to the digital age. He had this idea because of the Corona restrictions. Not only restaurants and shops were hit hard by this but also performers.</description></item><item><title>Migrate Azure Virtual Machine to On-Premise VMware Environment</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/migrate-azure-to-onprem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/migrate-azure-to-onprem/</guid><description>We recently updated a customer&amp;rsquo;s On-Premise infrastructure. He now has new Servers and Storage for his VMware ESXi 7.0 environment.
After moving all virtual machines to the new hardware (we used Veeam for this part of the migration), we also wanted to move one VM from Azure to the On-Premise infrastructure. This particular VM used to cause problems on the old infrastructure, and because of that, we moved it to Azure.</description></item><item><title>Printer deployment with Group Policy Preferences and error 0x80070bcb</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/printer-deployment-0x80070bcb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/printer-deployment-0x80070bcb/</guid><description>TL;DR
If you get the error 0x80070bcb when deploying your printers follow the instructions below.
Enable and configure these two GPO&amp;rsquo;s for all clients you want to deploy the printers to:
Computer Configuration &amp;gt; Policies &amp;gt; Administrative Templates &amp;gt; Printers &amp;gt; Package Point and print - Approved servers`
Computer Configuration &amp;gt; Policies &amp;gt; Administrative Templates &amp;gt; Printers &amp;gt; Point and Print Restrictions`
Configure them as follows:</description></item><item><title>How to upgrade your MacBook Pro 13" 2019 to a 2020 Model for free (Not Clickbait)</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/how-to-upgrade-your-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/how-to-upgrade-your-macbook-pro/</guid><description>So last year, I bought myself a new MacBook Pro 13-Inch 2019 Model in April 2019. My MacBook Air served me well, but it was time for an upgrade because I was getting more into programming, and I just needed the extra power.
Later this year, during quarantine, I upgraded my Home Office setup by getting a 49-Inch ultrawide monitor. It was the DELL U4919DW monitor to be specific. The great thing about it was that the monitor had an integrated USB-C docking station.</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2016 Hybrid setup false password/username</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/exchange-hybrid-2016-false-password/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/exchange-hybrid-2016-false-password/</guid><description>TL;DR
Don&amp;rsquo;t copy and paste the credentials. Type them in manually, and the setup will proceed normally.
I am currently doing a general infrastructure update for a customer. During this process, we migrated all Users from Exchange 2010 to Office 365 Mailboxes. But due to how Microsoft (sadly) designed their Office 365 with an On-premise Active Directory environment, you still need a local Exchange Server to manage the Exchange attributes in your On-Prem Active Directory [read the doc].</description></item><item><title>Essential tools for engineers</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/essential-tools-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/essential-tools-engineers/</guid><description>In this post, I will list some tools I use daily, explain why I use them, and provide a link to download/use them. I will regularly update this post if I find new tools or when they get discontinued.
Security 1Password
Great tool for iOS and macOS users to save passwords (it&amp;rsquo;s also available for other platforms). I would strongly suggest using a good password manager and not reuse passwords because the reuse of passwords is a serious security issue!</description></item><item><title>My first blog post</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/first-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/first-blog-post/</guid><description>Welcome to lorisscandurra.com! This is the first blog post on my new website. This blog is here to document the everyday issues I encounter during my work. This blog should help engineers solve some of their problems and help me remember the solutions I found in the past. I might also post some posts that are out of context about stuff I find interesting or entertaining.
I wanted to use this blog post to introduce myself better.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/about/</guid><description>test</description></item></channel></rss>