<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on lorisscandurra</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on lorisscandurra</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://lsca94.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moderne Prozessdigitalisierung - Teil 2</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/epost-digitalisierung-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/epost-digitalisierung-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prozess-digitalisierung-ai-services-in-unseren-geschäftsprozessen">
 Prozess-Digitalisierung: AI Services in unseren Geschäftsprozessen
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#prozess-digitalisierung-ai-services-in-unseren-gesch%c3%a4ftsprozessen">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Im letzten &lt;a href="https://blog.unscripted.ch/post/epost-digitalisierung-1/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blog Beitrag&lt;/a> haben wir einen einen Workflow erstellt um Dateien von ePost in unsere SharePoint Ablage zu speichern. Leider gibt uns der ePost Service keine aussagekräftigen Namen für unsere Dateien. Das wollen wir in diesem Artikel verbesssern, in dem wir Azure AI Services verwenden.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="was-sind-azure-ai-services">
 Was sind Azure AI Services?
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#was-sind-azure-ai-services">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Azure AI Services bietet eine Palette von AI-Diensten, einschliesslich Textgenerierung, Bildverarbeitung und Übersetzung. Ein Vorteil ist die Nutzung von Microsofts vortrainierten Modellen, wodurch eigenes Training für einfache Aufgaben entfällt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moderne Prozessdigitalisierung - Teil 1</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/epost-digitalisierung-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/epost-digitalisierung-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="digitalisierung-im-geschäftsalltag-ein-leitfaden-für-business-leader">
 Digitalisierung im Geschäftsalltag: Ein Leitfaden für Business Leader
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#digitalisierung-im-gesch%c3%a4ftsalltag-ein-leitfaden-f%c3%bcr-business-leader">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In der heutigen, von Technologie durchdrungenen Welt ist die Digitalisierung von Geschäftsprozessen nicht mehr nur ein &amp;ldquo;Nice-to-have&amp;rdquo;, sondern ein Muss. In diesem Artikel zeige ich dir, wie du mit modernen Tools wie ePost und Azure Logic Apps deine Geschäftsprozesse optimieren kannst.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="warum-prozessdigitalisierung">
 Warum Prozessdigitalisierung?
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#warum-prozessdigitalisierung">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Der Fachkräftemangel ist eine wachsende Herausforderung. Hier kommt die Prozessdigitalisierung ins Spiel: Sie ermöglicht es Unternehmen, effizienter und wettbewerbsfähiger zu werden und den Mangel an qualifiziertem Personal zu kompensieren. Automatisierte Systeme, cloudbasierte Lösungen und innovative Algorithmen können Unternehmen dabei helfen, ihre Workflows zu optimieren.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My lunilo.live journey</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/lunilo-live-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/lunilo-live-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the 10th of November 2020, a friend added me to a group call to discuss a startup idea. It was my friend, a guy I didn&amp;rsquo;t know yet, and me in the group call. The guy I didn&amp;rsquo;t know, named Luzius, had the idea to bring local artists, entertainers, comedians, performers to the digital age. He had this idea because of the Corona restrictions. Not only restaurants and shops were hit hard by this but also performers. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t perform in front of big crowds or any crowds anymore.&lt;br>
So the idea was to give them a platform to perform live. YouTube and Twitch don&amp;rsquo;t address this kind of artist because you need a huge following to survive on those platforms. So our idea was to put a paywall for the live performances. So we started the project with high hopes and dreams. The name of the platform was lunilo.live.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrate Azure Virtual Machine to On-Premise VMware Environment</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/migrate-azure-to-onprem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/migrate-azure-to-onprem/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently updated a customer&amp;rsquo;s On-Premise infrastructure. He now has new Servers and Storage for his VMware ESXi 7.0 environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After moving all virtual machines to the new hardware (we used Veeam for this part of the migration), we also wanted to move one VM from Azure to the On-Premise infrastructure. This particular VM used to cause problems on the old infrastructure, and because of that, we moved it to Azure. We made this migration to Azure also with Veeam. But Veeam didn&amp;rsquo;t have an option to move the VM back from Azure to the new VMware environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Printer deployment with Group Policy Preferences and error 0x80070bcb</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/printer-deployment-0x80070bcb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/printer-deployment-0x80070bcb/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you get the error 0x80070bcb when deploying your printers follow the instructions below.&lt;br>
Enable and configure these two GPO&amp;rsquo;s for all clients you want to deploy the printers to:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Computer Configuration &amp;gt; Policies &amp;gt; Administrative Templates &amp;gt; Printers &amp;gt; Package Point and print - Approved servers`&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Computer Configuration &amp;gt; Policies &amp;gt; Administrative Templates &amp;gt; Printers &amp;gt; Point and Print Restrictions`&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Configure them as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Policy &lt;code>Package Point and print - Approved servers&lt;/code> I had to add the FQDN of the print server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to upgrade your MacBook Pro 13" 2019 to a 2020 Model for free (Not Clickbait)</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/how-to-upgrade-your-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/how-to-upgrade-your-macbook-pro/</guid><description>&lt;p>So last year, I bought myself a new MacBook Pro 13-Inch 2019 Model in April 2019. My MacBook Air served me well, but it was time for an upgrade because I was getting more into programming, and I just needed the extra power.&lt;br>
Later this year, during quarantine, I upgraded my Home Office setup by getting a 49-Inch ultrawide monitor. It was the &lt;a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-ultrasharp-49-curved-monitor-u4919dw/apd/210-arnw/monitors-monitor-accessories" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DELL U4919DW&lt;/a> monitor to be specific. The great thing about it was that the monitor had an integrated USB-C docking station. I could now power my MacBook and transfer the video with just one cable plugged into it. This setup should look super clean.&lt;br>
After the new monitor arrived, I plugged my MacBook into it, but to my surprise, it just gave me a 3840x1080px resolution. That resolution was just horrible on that ultrawide monitor. I thought maybe some settings on the monitor were wrong, or I had to do some settings on my MacBook. Because officially, the 2019 MacBook should support up to 5K [&lt;a href="https://teamscandurra.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/mbp13_2019_5ksupport.pdf" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">read the specs&lt;/a>].&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exchange 2016 Hybrid setup false password/username</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/exchange-hybrid-2016-false-password/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/exchange-hybrid-2016-false-password/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Don&amp;rsquo;t copy and paste the credentials. Type them in manually, and the setup will proceed normally.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I am currently doing a general infrastructure update for a customer. During this process, we migrated all Users from Exchange 2010 to Office 365 Mailboxes. But due to how Microsoft (sadly) designed their Office 365 with an On-premise Active Directory environment, you still need a local Exchange Server to manage the Exchange attributes in your On-Prem Active Directory [&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/exchange/decommission-on-premises-exchange" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">read the doc&lt;/a>]. And because we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to leave an old Exchange Server with Windows 2008 R2 running in the network, we decided to install a new Exchange Server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Essential tools for engineers</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/essential-tools-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/essential-tools-engineers/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post, I will list some tools I use daily, explain why I use them, and provide a link to download/use them. I will regularly update this post if I find new tools or when they get discontinued.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="security">
 Security
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#security">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>1Password&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Great tool for iOS and macOS users to save passwords (it&amp;rsquo;s also available for other platforms). I would strongly suggest using a good password manager and not reuse passwords because the reuse of passwords is a serious security issue! 1Password is a paid tool, but there are also free options on the market like KeePass.&lt;br>
Link: &lt;a href="https://1password.com" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1password.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My first blog post</title><link>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/first-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://lsca94.github.io/posts/first-blog-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to lorisscandurra.com! This is the first blog post on my new website. This blog is here to document the everyday issues I encounter during my work. This blog should help engineers solve some of their problems and help me remember the solutions I found in the past. I might also post some posts that are out of context about stuff I find interesting or entertaining.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to use this blog post to introduce myself better. My name is Loris Scandurra, but you can just call me Loris. I am an engineer and project manager. For the past 10 years, I worked in the IT sector, where I solved problems ranging from client/server engineering to front-end/back-end development. But my interest in technology and science began a lot earlier than that. In elementary school, I would enjoy math and physics classes. As soon as I started reading, my favorite books were history and science-related.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>